Alex Brown

"Cyber. Space. Intelligence." Yelm, WA 98597

T 360 393 7255 abrowncownow@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/abrowncownow



SUMMARY

Skilled veteran with expertise in IT, analysis, and strategy. High level of integrity and reliability. Enjoy the design and implementation of efficient solutions to complex problems.

Currently employed as an Engineer (Hardware) for Worldwide Tech Services. Intend to move into a more career-oriented position. Volunteer actor and musician.

EXPERIENCE

IT Hardware Engineer, Worldwide Tech Services Olympia, WA — 01/2021 - Current

Perform onsite troubleshooting and warranty repair for Dell, HP, and Lenovo systems for commercial, government, and residential clients. Independently manage scheduling. Maintain more than 25 IT certifications on different equipment.

All Source Intelligence Analyst, US ARMY

Fort Hood, Texas -01/2012 - 04/2015

Aggregated information from different sources into a single finished intelligence product. Advised leaders regularly. Coordinated with intergovernmental organizations. Enforced security regulations.

Accomplishments

- Awarded Army Achievement Medal for correctly anticipating location of enemy minefield through intelligence analysis
- Secure sensitive classified technology valued ~ \$1.8 million.
- Automated monthly security clearance reporting processes.

CLEARANCE

TOP SECRET

- Current through 2017
- TS/SCI
- Level 6 JPAS Access
- Clearance Manager
- Classified Network Operator

SKILLS

- Excellent Interpersonal Skills
- Computer Troubleshooting
- Advanced Critical Thinking
- Windows Systems Admin
- Advanced Windows Office
- 90 WPM Typing SpeedLinux Experience
- •

CERTIFICATION

- Linux Operations
- Space Cadre I & II
- Enhanced Analytics
- Remote Satellite Ops
- o 25+ IT Certificates
- Combat Lifesaver

Responsibilities

- Utilize critical thinking skills and analytical tools to identify and assess future risks, in order to recommend strategies and solutions to leadership.
- Train and manage a team of analysts to perform regular audits of military weapon rooms to ensure compliance with strict federal regulations.
- Coach new soldiers in aspects of adjusting to the organization, area, and military demands.
- Work closely with leadership to identify and resolve serious internal incidents. Coordinate with local law enforcement.

Customer Service Representative, *T-Mobile* Bellingham, WA – 1/2011-11/2011

Worked as part of a 15 member team in a medium-sized call center that managed and updated customer accounts and troubleshooted Android/iOS devices over the phone.

Consultant/Owner, AZTEK

Yelm, WA - 10/2019-Bellingham, WA - 5/2009-11/2011 Woodland, WA - 7/2008-5/2009

Run a technology consulting, sales, and repair business serving commercial and residential customers. Perform troubleshooting and resolution of a variety of IT problems.

Services Offered

- Small network (5-15 node) design and implementation
- Custom PC building and imaging.
- Computer hardware repair/upgrade.
- Software and network troubleshooting.
- Virus removal and prevention.

EDUCATION

Evergreen State College Olympia, WA - 2019-2021 *Bachelor Degree*

Grays Harbor College Aberdeen, WA - 2017-2019 Progress towards BA

Cochise College Tucson, AZ - 2012 22 Credits towards Intelligence AS

Lower Columbia College Longview, WA - 2007 Offered full scholarship for acting

Gonzaga University Spokane, WA - 2006 Summer business program sponsored by Boeing and Microsoft

VOLUNTEER

Triad Arts Theater Yelm, WA - 2016-2017 The Mousetrap - Sergeant Trotter Monty Python's Spamalot - Multiple

Love Street Playhouse Woodland, WA - 2008 Charlotte's Web - Templeton + addl. It's a Wonderful Life - Stage Mgr. Night of January 16th - Dr. Kirkland

Columbia Theater Longview, WA - 2007 The Bald Soprano - Fire chief

Woodland Community Center Woodland, WA - 2006 Summer volunteer